<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cisco on Nathan Curry</title>
    <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/categories/cisco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cisco on Nathan Curry</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.nathancurry.com/categories/cisco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack Ansible Installation, Part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/29-openstack-ansible-part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/29-openstack-ansible-part4/</guid>
      <description>In parts 1 through 3, I&amp;rsquo;ve prepared my hosts and network environment for a smooth deployment. Please see those previous articles if you are using this as a reference.
Now comes the actual deployment.
Overview Since this is my first OpenStack deployment (other than an AiO RDO deploy in a VM), I used the openstack-ansible &amp;ldquo;test&amp;rdquo; configuration so I could have a fairly complete, functional setup.
To customize the install, you have to copy relevant files to /etc/openstack_deploy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack Ansible Installation, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/28-openstack-ansible-part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/28-openstack-ansible-part3/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I configured the system network configuration on the OpenStack nodes, but I still have to configure VLAN access on the switch.
Overview Each system has two NICs, in large part to keep storage traffic on its own collision domain. The vlans are assigned thusly:
nic1: br-mgmt: purpose: &amp;#39;management traffic, admin&amp;#39; vlan: &amp;#39;native&amp;#39; network: &amp;#39;10.3.2.0/23&amp;#39; br-storage: purpose: &amp;#39;storage traffic&amp;#39; vlan: &amp;#39;5&amp;#39; network: &amp;#39;10.3.5.0/24&amp;#39; nic2: br-vlan: purpose: &amp;#39;non-tunneled virtual network&amp;#39; vlan: &amp;#39;native&amp;#39; network: &amp;#39;10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco ICND1 Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/05-icnd1-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 16:08:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/05-icnd1-recap/</guid>
      <description>I just tentatively passed the ICND1 with a 925&amp;sol;1000, and I&amp;rsquo;m pleased with my performance. Obviously, I am honor-bound (and perhaps more importantly, legally bound) to not discuss the exam contents.
Preparation I began studying in late April. At the suggestion of a family friend and retired CCIE, I worked off the following materials:
 An all-in-one rack on eBay that had 3 1841 routers, 2 layer2 switches, and 1 layer3 switch for $300.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCENT Lab Notes, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/03-ccent-lab-notes-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/03-ccent-lab-notes-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This is a continuation of my previous notes on CCENT labs. These Ranet labs are significantly better-designed than the previous set of labs, though the evaluation at the end of the exam doesn&amp;rsquo;t always work.
These are my notes for all the labs that deal with ICND1 objectives, and I will save the ICND2 objectives for later when I review.
SPOILERS: DO NOT CONTINUE READING IF YOU PLAN ON DOING THE LABS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCENT Lab Notes, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/02-ccent-lab-notes-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/02-ccent-lab-notes-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a log of my work on last 6 of these PackTracer labs for the ICND1 exam.
SPOILER ALERT: Do your labs first, these are notes on how I resolved them.
Lab 7  PC0 cannot ping PC1, can you fix it?
 I verify that both PCs can ping as far as the outward-facing interface of R3. I furthermore verify that both R3 can ping R1, but not from its inside interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCENT Lab Notes, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/01-ccent-lab-notes-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/01-ccent-lab-notes-part-1/</guid>
      <description>This is a log of my work on the first 6 of these PackTracer labs for the ICND1 exam.
SPOILERS FOLLOW!!! This is not a guide on how to approach the problems, it&amp;rsquo;s a review of completed work. This perhaps has educational merit, but please continue only after having completed the labs yourself.
Lab 1  Switch0 is configured as DHCP server but not working. Can you fix it?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>