<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Nathan Curry</title>
    <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Nathan Curry</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Kickstarts With Ansible</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/21-generate-kickstarts-with-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/21-generate-kickstarts-with-ansible/</guid>
      <description>I wanted a way to generate kickstart files so I can easily spin up new VMs. I will also be making use of cloning, but I want to have a PXE boot server at some point as well.
I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to test a deployment&amp;ndash;and I&amp;rsquo;m sure there&amp;rsquo;s still tweaking to do&amp;ndash;but the workflow is complete.
You can find the relevant git commit here.
Overview tasks/ └── make_kickstarts.yml roles/kickstart/ ├── tasks │ └── main.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Time Services With Ansible</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/20-configuring-chrony-with-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/20-configuring-chrony-with-ansible/</guid>
      <description>I put together an Ansible role for configuring network time services, using chrony.
This is my most elegant work thus far, though before this is worth packaging, I&amp;rsquo;d like to configure the scripts to test for Debian vs. Red Hat, as well as add variables for a few things.
You can take a look at the relevant git commit here.
Structure Here are the files in this project. A task to call the roles, and a role for master/slave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Role For Local Repo</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/19-ansible-role-for-local-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/19-ansible-role-for-local-repo/</guid>
      <description>I need a local install source and system I can serve kickstart files from. I wrote an Ansible role to accomplish this. The kickstart process will be covered in the next article.
Here is the relevant git commit
Structure files/ # Static files centos7.repo # Sync source local.repo # Repo file for download tasks/ configure_repo.yml # Set up repo in container prepare_host_node.yml # Prepare Proxmox node main.yml # Main script main.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>String Replacement With Shell One-Liners</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/18-shell-one-liners-for-string-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/18-shell-one-liners-for-string-replacement/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m about to start working on installing FreeIPA servers, and I need to make a few small changes to variables as stored. The most efficient way was to use a few one-liners.
Rename inventory I want to rename all ansible hosts as their FQDN. I attack the ini-style inventory file like so:
nc@tiny: ~/0/homelab.ansible/ $ sed -i &amp;#34;s/[a-z1-9]$/&amp;amp;.lan.nathancurry.com/&amp;#34; inventory This simply matches each line that ends in either a letter or a number, and appends (the &amp;amp; operator) the rest of the FQDN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Workflow 1: Spin Up DNS/DHCP Failover Pair</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/17-ansible-workflow-deploying-dns-dhcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/17-ansible-workflow-deploying-dns-dhcp/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on getting the individual pieces put together on this, and I finally have the entire thing working. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a playbook workflow that will deploy two containers, install BIND and ISC DHCPD, and start them.
What it will not do is update DNS automatically. I&amp;rsquo;m able to update the DNS manually with nsupdate, but it appears as though DHCPD isn&amp;rsquo;t even trying. For now, I&amp;rsquo;m moving on, and I will revisit with fresh eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating BIND Config From Ansible hostvars</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/16-generating-bind-entries-from-ansible-hostvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/16-generating-bind-entries-from-ansible-hostvars/</guid>
      <description>Since streamlining my container deployment, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on automating a BIND deployment. I found this excellent role over at MangoLassi.it, and I&amp;rsquo;m tailoring it to my needs.
Generating based on hostvars For now, I&amp;rsquo;m statically mapping IPs, MAC addresses, and a few other machine facts in host_vars, so that I have a defined infrastructure, even when the hosts don&amp;rsquo;t exist.
fqdn: &amp;#39;ns.lan.nathancurry.com&amp;#39; ip_address: &amp;#39;10.3.3.2&amp;#39; mac_address: &amp;#39;52:54:00:76:b4:78&amp;#39; services: [ &amp;#39;dns&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;dhcp&amp;#39; ] This allows me to keep key infrastructure facts in one place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize a CentOS LXC Container with Proxmox</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/15-customize-lxc-container-template-on-proxmox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/15-customize-lxc-container-template-on-proxmox/</guid>
      <description>The CentOS-based container template provided by Proxmox doesn&amp;rsquo;t have SSH installed, which makes it fairly useless for Ansible-based deployments.
Here are the steps to update and reroll a template:
Create and connect to the container The web UI is easy and fills out important info for you, but I created it through the CLI using a template I had preloaded.
root@gold:~# pct create 105 gluster:vztmpl/centos-7-default_20171212_amd64.tar.xz --storage local-lvm --net0 name=eth0,ip=dhcp,ip6=dhcp,bridge=vmbr0 --password=password root@gold:~# pct start 105 root@gold:~# pct console 105 Make desired changes You can do pretty much anything, but keep it simple:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Infrastructure on Proxmox with Ansible</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/14-ansible-deployment-with-proxmox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/14-ansible-deployment-with-proxmox/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve broken down my HomeLab, and I&amp;rsquo;m rebuilding it in Ansible for deployment on a Proxmox cluster.
Configure Proxmox for ansible I&amp;rsquo;ve been working off morph027&amp;rsquo;s workflow for a first successful run. He uses the ansible plugin proxmox_kvm, and I&amp;rsquo;m using proxmox (for containers).
Infrastructure Short and sweet:
[proxmox] gold silver bronze Setup script To get my blood pumping, I wrote a playbook to configure the three nodes:
# install_pip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a Third Proxmox&#43;Gluster Node</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/13-adding-third-proxmox-gluster-node/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/13-adding-third-proxmox-gluster-node/</guid>
      <description>I freed up the system I was using to do data recovery is free, and so I&amp;rsquo;m finally adding my third node to my Proxmox+Gluster cluster.
Install Proxmox Same as before, allocated 8GB for swap, 10GB max for root, and 200GB for extra LVM partitions.
Create the gluster brick I ran into an issue that I had one fewer available physical extents on this disk due to it being a different model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxmox VE 5.2-1 with a GlusterFS Store</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/11-proxmox-ve-with-glusterfs-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/11-proxmox-ve-with-glusterfs-store/</guid>
      <description>I had initially planned on migrating from plain KVM to oVirt. My reasoning was thus:
 oVirt is the upstream of Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization, and I plan on pursuing higher Red Hat certifications It inegrates with OpenStack, another technology adopted by Red Hat It&amp;rsquo;s robust and flexible  However, upon installing * Documentation for RHEV is complete, but behind a version or two * Documentation for oVirt is poorly maintained, and some documents stop almost mid-sentence * Terraform plugins for oVirt are not ready for primetime * The network management is needlessly ornate</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-Node GlusterFS on oVirt Node 4.2.5.1</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/09-two-node-glusterfs-on-ovirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/09-two-node-glusterfs-on-ovirt/</guid>
      <description>Generally speaking, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t configure two nodes in a Gluster, since data divergence is resolved by a vote among the nodes. However, my third bare metal host is currently occupied recovering data from a dying hard drive, so I&amp;rsquo;m doing this for now and adding the third brick later.
Install oVirt I booted the oVirt 4.2 installer ISO off a flash drive, and made only minor changes.
I took the suggested partition scheme, but reduced the root partition to 8GiB, and used the spare space for my glusterfs partition, formatting it XFS and mounting it on /glusterfs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerberized NFS with FreeIPA on CentOS 7 and Fedora 28</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/07-kerberized-nfs-with-freeipa-on-centos-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/07-kerberized-nfs-with-freeipa-on-centos-7/</guid>
      <description>I have an NFS server on a KVM guest, and I want to integrate auth into my IdM server so I can have an automount readily accessible from any of the hosts.
Most of my hosts are CentOS 7, but my personal laptop is running Fedora 28.
What I&amp;rsquo;ve done already  The FreeIPA server is already installed (refer to the Red Hat 7 IdM Install Guide) Replica is already installed and providing failover CA and DNS services Hosts are registered with the FreeIPA server  Configure FreeIPA You need to add the service to both the client and server:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KVM Guest Raw Disk Access</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/06-kvm-guest-raw-disk-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/06-kvm-guest-raw-disk-access/</guid>
      <description>In the process of setting up my NFS server, I ran into how best to attach a USB3 disk directly to the KVM guest for direct writethrough.
Pools vs. Raw My criteria for the solution were as follows:
 Portability. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be stuck with a disk I can&amp;rsquo;t read without KVM tools. Speed. I&amp;rsquo;m actually going to be using this disk. Low overhead. I don&amp;rsquo;t need KVM to worry about the disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco ICND1 Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/05-icnd1-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 16:08:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/05-icnd1-recap/</guid>
      <description>I just tentatively passed the ICND1 with a 925&amp;sol;1000, and I&amp;rsquo;m pleased with my performance. Obviously, I am honor-bound (and perhaps more importantly, legally bound) to not discuss the exam contents.
Preparation I began studying in late April. At the suggestion of a family friend and retired CCIE, I worked off the following materials:
 An all-in-one rack on eBay that had 3 1841 routers, 2 layer2 switches, and 1 layer3 switch for $300.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCENT Lab Notes, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/03-ccent-lab-notes-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/03-ccent-lab-notes-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This is a continuation of my previous notes on CCENT labs. These Ranet labs are significantly better-designed than the previous set of labs, though the evaluation at the end of the exam doesn&amp;rsquo;t always work.
These are my notes for all the labs that deal with ICND1 objectives, and I will save the ICND2 objectives for later when I review.
SPOILERS: DO NOT CONTINUE READING IF YOU PLAN ON DOING THE LABS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCENT Lab Notes, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/02-ccent-lab-notes-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/02-ccent-lab-notes-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a log of my work on last 6 of these PackTracer labs for the ICND1 exam.
SPOILER ALERT: Do your labs first, these are notes on how I resolved them.
Lab 7  PC0 cannot ping PC1, can you fix it?
 I verify that both PCs can ping as far as the outward-facing interface of R3. I furthermore verify that both R3 can ping R1, but not from its inside interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat EX200 Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/04-ex200-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 12:02:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/04-ex200-recap/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an RHCSA as of August 17th, and I figured I&amp;rsquo;d jot down a few notes about my preparation, successes, and failures.
Preparation My materials to prepare for this exam:
 CBT Nuggets System Administrator Prep videos
 Michael Jang&amp;rsquo;s RCHSA/RHCE 7 book
 Some free online practice exams
 3x micro PCs for hypervisors
  The CBT Nuggets video series was rudimentary, but it has one of the better intros into SELinux that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCENT Lab Notes, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/01-ccent-lab-notes-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nathancurry.com/blog/01-ccent-lab-notes-part-1/</guid>
      <description>This is a log of my work on the first 6 of these PackTracer labs for the ICND1 exam.
SPOILERS FOLLOW!!! This is not a guide on how to approach the problems, it&amp;rsquo;s a review of completed work. This perhaps has educational merit, but please continue only after having completed the labs yourself.
Lab 1  Switch0 is configured as DHCP server but not working. Can you fix it?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>